

Anton, Yuanhuiyi LYU

HKUST · RESEARCH ASSISTANT

【 (+86)15898223029 | ■ lvyuanhuiyi@foxmail.com | 🔏 qc-ly.github.io/ | 🖸 github.com/QC-LY | 🖘 Yuanhuiyi Lyu

Personal Profile

I'm now a research assistant supervised by **Dr. Addison L. Wang** at **HKUST**. I obtained my B.ENG in Artificial Intelligence from Northeastern University (**NEU**). My research interests include **Multi-modal learning**, **Embodied Vision**, and **Generative Models**.

Education

Northeastern University

Bachelor in Artificial Intelligence

Shenyang, China

Sept 2019 - June 2023

• GPA: **87.39**/100

• Courses: Object-Oriented Programming(C++) (98), Data Structure/Algorithm (91), Optimization Methods (91), Machine Learning (95), Linear Algebra (88), Probability Theory and Mathematical Statistics (94), Natural Language Processing (85), Computer Graphics (90)

Research Experience_

VLIS Lab, Hong Kong University of Science and Technology

Guangzhou & Hong Kong

June 2023 - present

• Supevisor: Addison L. Wang

• Research Area: Multi-modal Learning, Embodied Vision, 3D Vision.

NLP Lab, Tsinghua University

Beijing, China

Research Intern

Research Intern

Research Assistant

Oct 2021 - Dec 2022

Supevisor: Zhenghao Liu, Chenyan Xiong, Zhiyuan Liu
 Research Area: Multi-modal Learning, Information Retrieval.

NLP Lab, Northeastern University

Shenyang, China

June 2021 - Sept 2021

• Supevisor: Tong Xiao

• Research Area: Text Generation.

Publications

OmniBind: Teach to Build Unequal-Scale Modality Interaction for Omni-Bind of All

Yuanhuiyi Lyu, Xu Zheng, Dahun Kim, Lin Wang

arXiv preprint arXiv:2405.16108 (2024). 2024

Image Anything: Towards Reasoning-coherent and Training-free Multi-modal Image Generation

Yuanhuiyi Lyu, Xu Zheng, Lin Wang

arXiv preprint arXiv:2401.17664 (2024). 2024

UniBind: LLM-Augmented Unified and Balanced Representation Space to Bind Them All

Yuanhuiyi Lyu, Xu Zheng, Jiazhou Zhou, Lin Wang

The IEEE/CVF Conference on Computer Vision and Pattern Recognition (CVPR) (2024). 2024

EIT-1M: One Million EEG-Image-Text Pairs for Human Visual-textual Recognition and More

Xu Zheng, Ling Wang, Kanghao Chen, **Yuanhuiyi Lyu**, Jiazhou Zhou, Lin Wang

arXiv preprint arXiv:2407.01884 (2024). 2024

Centering the Value of Every Modality: Towards Efficient and Resilient Modality-agnostic Semantic Segmentation Xu Zheng, **Yuanhuiyi Lyu**, Lin Wang

The European Conference on Computer Vision (ECCV) (2024). 2024

Learning Modality-agnostic Representation for Semantic Segmentation from Any Modalities

Xu Zheng, Yuanhuiyi Lyu, Lin Wang

The European Conference on Computer Vision (**ECCV**) (2024). 2024

EventBind: Learning a Unified Representation to Bind Them All for Event-based Open-world Understanding

Jiazhou Zhou, Xu Zheng, Yuanhuiyi Lyu, Lin Wang

The European Conference on Computer Vision (ECCV) (2024). 2024

ExACT: Language-guided Conceptual Reasoning and Uncertainty Estimation for Event-based Action Recognition and More Jiazhou Zhou, Xu Zheng, **Yuanhuiyi Lyu**, Lin Wang

JULY 14, 2024

Componerf: Text-guided multi-object compositional nerf with editable 3d scene layout Haotian Bai, **Yuanhuiyi Lyu**, Lutao Jiang, Si Jia Li, Haonan Lu, Xiaodong Lin, Lin Wang arXiv preprint arXiv:2303.13843 (2023). 2023

Chasing Day and Night: Towards Robust and Efficient All-Day Object Detection Guided by an Event Camera Jiahang Cao, Xu Zheng, **Yuanhuiyi Lyu**, Jiaxu Wang, Renjing Xu, Lin Wang

The 2024 IEEE International Conference on Robotics and Automation (ICRA) (2023). 2023

Universal Vision-Language Dense Retrieval: Learning A Unified Representation Space for Multi-Modal Retrieval Zhenghao Liu, Chenyan Xiong, **Yuanhuiyi Lv**, Zhiyuan Liu, Ge Yu

The Eleventh International Conference on Learning Representations (ICLR) (2023). 2023

Open-Source Projects

Fundus Image Segmentation Base On U-Net

Shenyang, China

Key Laboratory in Intelligent Medical Image Computing at Northeastern University

June 2022 - Sept 2022

- The code is open source at https://github.com/QC-LY/Fundus-Image-Segmentation

Prompt Tuning For Sentiment Classification Base On Pre-trained Language Models NEU NLP Lab

Shenyang, China

June 2021 - Sept 2021

 $\bullet \ \, \text{The code is open source at $https://github.com/QC-LY/Prompt-Tuning-For-Sentiment-Classification} \\$

Honors and Awards(Selected)

| 2023 | Outstanding Graduation Dissertation (<2%), Northeastern University | Shenyang, China |
|------|--|-----------------|
| 2022 | Outstanding Students Scholarship, Northeastern University | Shenyang, China |
| 2021 | Outstanding Students Scholarship, Northeastern University | Shenyang, China |
| 2020 | Outstanding Students Scholarship, Northeastern University | Shenyang, China |
| | | |

JULY 14, 2024